Inventory of the Robert R. Bramlett Papers 1966-1967
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Robert R. Bramlett Papers 1966-1967
Special Collections Research Center
01/Mss. Acc. 2009.306, 2011.114, and 2011.127
0.80
Bramlett, B. R. arrangement
Administrative Information
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open to all researchers.
Acquisition Information
The materials were acquired by Special Collections Research Center on 07/22/2009.
Biographical Note
B.R. Bramlett was marine sergeant stationed in Vietnam. He was an MP, and later brig warden, at Phu Bai and Danang after being in the infantry. He was in charge of imprisoned American soldiers as well as Vietnamese prisoners of war. Further information about this individual or organization may be available in the Special Collections Research Center Wiki: http://scrc.swem.wm.edu/wiki/index.php/B. R. Bramlett.
Scope and Contents
This collection is composed of letters from B.R. Bramlett to his wife written while on active duty with the Marine Corps during the Vietnam War, 1966-1967. Topics include everyday concerns for his family at home, and descriptions of his military duties. In describing racial tensions between the black and white American troops Bramlett labels the black troops repeatedly as 'trouble makers'. In each letter he expresses his love and devotion to his wife and children, and often writes about worrying that he has left his wife with difficult responsibilities, such as getting the car fixed, dealing with household problems, and caring for two young children. The collection includes some letters to Bramlett from his wife, who frequently reassures him that she and the children are doing well. In several June 1967 letters, Bramlett advises his wife on paperwork regarding her pending United States citizenship.
Arrangement of Materials
Arranged chronologically.
Additional Information
Index Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Genre/Form of Material:
Letters (correspondence)
Topical Term:
Race relations--1960-1970; Vietnam War, 1961-1975--Personal narratives, American
Detailed Description of the Collection
- id88202 (Box 1)
  - Letters, January 1966-November 1966; id88203 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letters, December 1966; id88204 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Letters, January 1967; id88205 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Letters, February 1967; id88206 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Letters, March 1967-April 1967; id88207 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Letters, May 1967; id88208 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- id88209 (Box 2)
  - Letters, June 1967-July 1967; id88210 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Letters, August 1967; id88211 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Letters, September 1967; id88212 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Letters, Octobe 1967; id88213 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Letters, November 1967-December 1967; id88214 (Box 2, Folder 5)